Taylor Massey

Denver, CO | 301-788-9136 | tamassey92@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Certified Full Stack Developer with front and back-end programming experience. Excellent communicator, detail-oriented, and a team player as strongly demonstrated in 10+ years of client-facing roles. Eager to engage in programming opportunities where my passion for problem-solving can be utilized.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, React, HTML, & CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Bucket List - Github | Demo

Users draw inspiration to create their own Bucket-List.

- Shared data between a React frontend and a Rails backend with GET, POST, & DELETE actions.
- Utilized React Router to create 3 client-side routes in a single-page application.
- Wrote custom CSS for styling.

Recipe Tracker - Github | Demo

Allows users to search, add, delete, and view recipes through different categories.

- Utilized React & Sinatra to build out front and back-end capabilities.
- Used Active Record to access and interact with the recipe database.
- Implemented full CRUD capability for recipes through Sinatra.

Caption This Meme - Github | Demo

This app generates memes and allows users to like and add captions.

- Utilized JSON to access and fetch meme data from a public API.
- Added click, submit, and mouseover event listeners to engage users.
- Manipulated API data through for Each array iteration method.

EXPERIENCE

Advocates for Children CASA

Denver, CO

Volunteer Coordinator

11/2020 - 09/2021

- Recruited over 100 volunteers to serve the needs of the organization.
- Increased retention of new volunteers by 20% using Excel to update the onboarding process.

Volo City Sports & Kids Foundation

Baltimore, MD 05/2017 - 05/2018

Events Manager

- Planned & executed various style events for up to 2,500 attendees.
- Recruited and managed volunteers & staff for VOLO adult and kids leagues.
- Led the launch of a new market in Washington, D.C., with attention to detail, quick problem-solving, & an organized plan for success.

The Living Legacy Foundation

Baltimore, MD

Community Outreach Associate

03/2015 - 05/2017

- Assisted in events coordination & creation of LLF educational and promotional materials.
- Coordinated high school educational program & presentations.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

04/2022 - 07/2022

Quinnipiac University

Hamden, CT

Bachelor of Arts in Communication - Journalism

05/2014